<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc [
]>
<rfc xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
     category="info"
     submissionType="independent"
     docName="draft-digitaldefiance-wcap-00"
     ipr="trust200902"
     
     xml:lang="en"
     version="3">

  <front>
    <title abbrev="WCAP">Web Content Authenticity Protocol (WCAP)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-digitaldefiance-wcap-00"/>

    <author fullname="Jessica Mulein" initials="J." surname="Mulein">
      <organization>Digital Defiance</organization>
      <address>
        <email>jessica@digitaldefiance.org</email>
        <uri>https://digitaldefiance.org</uri>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date year="2026" month="May"/>

    <area>Security</area>
    <workgroup>Independent Submission</workgroup>

    <keyword>content authenticity</keyword>
    <keyword>digital signature</keyword>
    <keyword>HTTP header</keyword>
    <keyword>integrity</keyword>

    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines the Web Content Authenticity Protocol (WCAP),
      a mechanism for ensuring the end-to-end authenticity and integrity of
      web resources. WCAP is designed to be transport-agnostic, meaning it
      can verify content regardless of how it was delivered — via HTTP,
      peer-to-peer networks, or other channels. By using digital signatures,
      WCAP allows a verifier to cryptographically confirm that a resource is
      exactly what the originator intended to publish, and has not been
      tampered with by any intermediary, including compromised servers,
      state-level actors, or malicious networks. Version 0.3 extends the
      protocol with an optional Signing Policy Declaration mechanism,
      allowing Signers to declare what they verified about content provenance
      and integrity before signing, enabling verifiers to distinguish
      transport-integrity-only signatures from signatures backed by deeper
      content verification.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>

  <middle>

    <section anchor="introduction">
      <name>Introduction</name>
      <t>While Transport Layer Security (TLS) provides a secure channel
      between a client and a server, it does not protect content once it
      has been delivered or if an intermediary in the chain (such as a CDN
      or proxy) is compromised. The Web Content Authenticity Protocol (WCAP)
      provides a mechanism for a web server (the "Signer") to digitally sign
      web resources, allowing a client (the "Verifier") to confirm that the
      content is exactly what the origin server intended to send.</t>

      <t>The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
      "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "NOT RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and
      "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be interpreted as described in
      BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119"/> <xref target="RFC8174"/> when, and
      only when, they appear in all capitals, as shown here.</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="threat-model">
      <name>Threat Model</name>
      <t>WCAP is designed to protect against the following threats:</t>
      <dl>
        <dt>Content Injection/Modification</dt>
        <dd>A malicious actor alters content in transit.</dd>
        <dt>Compromised Infrastructure</dt>
        <dd>A CDN, reverse proxy, or hosting server is compromised.</dd>
        <dt>DNS Manipulation</dt>
        <dd>An adversary reroutes traffic to a malicious server.</dd>
        <dt>TLS Interception</dt>
        <dd>A rogue or coerced CA enables a man-in-the-middle attack.</dd>
        <dt>Censorship and Takedowns</dt>
        <dd>A government forces a platform to alter or remove content.</dd>
        <dt>Signer Coercion</dt>
        <dd>A publisher is forced to hand over their private signing keys.</dd>
        <dt>Provenance Ambiguity</dt>
        <dd>A Signer forwards content from an untrusted or unverified upstream
        source without disclosing this to the Verifier, causing the Verifier
        to incorrectly infer that the Signer vouches for the content's origin.
        The Signing Policy mechanism (Section 13) addresses this threat by
        making the Signer's verification posture explicit.</dd>
      </dl>
    </section>

    <section anchor="terminology">
      <name>Terminology</name>
      <dl>
        <dt>Resource</dt>
        <dd>Any HTTP-delivered content (HTML, JavaScript, images, JSON, etc.).</dd>
        <dt>Signer</dt>
        <dd>The server or entity that holds a private key and signs Resources.</dd>
        <dt>Verifier</dt>
        <dd>The client or tool that retrieves and verifies the Signature using the Signer's public key.</dd>
        <dt>Signature</dt>
        <dd>The result of signing a Resource body with a private key.</dd>
        <dt>Public Key URI</dt>
        <dd>A URI where the Signer's public key is published.</dd>
        <dt>Signing Policy</dt>
        <dd>A declared assurance level indicating what the Signer verified
        about the content before signing. Expressed as a registered token in
        the "policy" parameter of the Content-Signature header
        (Section 13).</dd>
      </dl>
    </section>

    <section anchor="quick-start">
      <name>Quick Start</name>

      <section anchor="qs-p256">
        <name>Example: P-256 (Default Suite)</name>
        <t>Step 1: Generate a Key Pair</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
openssl ecparam -name prime256v1 -genkey -noout -out private-key.pem
openssl ec -in private-key.pem -pubout -out public-key.pem
]]></artwork>
        <t>Step 2: Sign Your Content</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
openssl dgst -sha256 -sign private-key.pem -out signature.bin message.txt
openssl base64 -in signature.bin -out signature.b64
]]></artwork>
        <t>Step 3: Serve Content with Content-Signature Header</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
Content-Signature: alg=ecdsa-p256-sha256;
    key_uri=/.well-known/wcap-public-key.pem;
    sig=<base64 signature>
]]></artwork>
        <t>Ensure the public key is served at the path specified in key_uri.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="qs-dd-ecies">
        <name>Example: DD-ECIES (secp256k1 Suite)</name>
        <t>This example demonstrates signing content using the
        "dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256" algorithm suite. The signature uses
        ECDSA over secp256k1 with SHA-256, producing a 64-byte compact
        signature as defined in the DD-ECIES specification
        <xref target="DD-ECIES"/>.</t>

        <t>Step 1: Generate a secp256k1 Key Pair</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
openssl ecparam -name secp256k1 -genkey -noout \
    -out private-key-secp256k1.pem
openssl ec -in private-key-secp256k1.pem -pubout \
    -conv_form compressed -out public-key-secp256k1.pem
]]></artwork>
        <t>The public key MUST be a 33-byte compressed secp256k1 key
        (0x02 or 0x03 prefix byte) encoded in PEM format.</t>

        <t>Step 2: Sign Your Content</t>
        <t>Compute the SHA-256 hash of the content, then sign the hash
        using ECDSA with deterministic nonce generation per
        <xref target="RFC6979"/>. The resulting signature MUST be a
        64-byte compact format: r (32 bytes) || s (32 bytes), with no
        DER encoding. A DD-ECIES-compatible tool or library is required
        to produce the compact signature format.</t>

        <t>Step 3: Serve Content with Content-Signature Header</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
Content-Signature: alg=dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256;
    key_uri=/.well-known/wcap-public-key-secp256k1.pem;
    sig=<base64 compact signature>;
    kid=secp256k1-2025
]]></artwork>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="protocol-flow">
      <name>Protocol Flow</name>
      <ol>
        <li>The Verifier requests a Resource.</li>
        <li>The Signer generates the Resource body and its Signature.</li>
        <li>The Signer returns the Resource with the Content-Signature HTTP header.</li>
        <li>The Verifier retrieves the public key from key_uri.</li>
        <li>The Verifier checks the Signature against the Resource body.</li>
      </ol>
      <t>If verification succeeds, the Resource is authentic. If it fails,
      the Resource is potentially tampered with.</t>
    </section>

    <section anchor="server-requirements">
      <name>Server (Signer) Requirements</name>

      <section anchor="key-management">
        <name>Key Management</name>
        <ul>
          <li>Signers MUST generate and securely store a public/private key pair.</li>
          <li>RECOMMENDED algorithm: ECDSA (P-256 with SHA-256).</li>
          <li>Signers MAY support other modern, secure digital signature algorithms.</li>
          <li>Signers SHOULD rotate keys periodically and expose metadata for revocation and validity.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>

      <section anchor="public-key-publication">
        <name>Public Key Publication</name>
        <ul>
          <li>Signers MUST publish their public key at a stable key_uri, such as
          "/.well-known/wcap-public-key.pem".</li>
          <li>The key MUST be served over HTTPS with a valid certificate.</li>
          <li>The public key MUST be in PEM format.</li>
          <li>Signers MAY include a revocation URI and expiration metadata.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>

      <section anchor="content-signature-header">
        <name>The Content-Signature Header</name>
        <t>Header format:</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
Content-Signature: alg=<algorithm>; key_uri=<uri>;
    sig=<base64 signature>[; kid=<key-id>][; policy=<policy-token>]
]]></artwork>

        <section anchor="header-parameters">
          <name>Parameters</name>
          <dl>
            <dt>alg</dt>
            <dd>REQUIRED. Algorithm suite identifier. MUST be a registered
            identifier from the Algorithm Suite Registry
            (<xref target="algorithm-suite-registry"/>). Valid values include
            "ecdsa-p256-sha256" (default) and "dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256".</dd>

            <dt>key_uri</dt>
            <dd>REQUIRED. Public key location (relative or absolute URI).
            The key served at this URI MUST be in PEM format and MUST
            conform to the key format specified by the algorithm suite.</dd>

            <dt>sig</dt>
            <dd>REQUIRED. Base64-encoded (<xref target="RFC4648"/> Section 4) digital signature of the exact
            response body. The signature encoding and size MUST conform to
            the signature format specified by the algorithm suite.</dd>

            <dt>kid</dt>
            <dd>OPTIONAL. Key ID string identifying which key the signer
            used. This parameter supports signers that publish multiple keys
            (e.g., for different algorithm suites or key rotation). When
            present, verifiers SHOULD use the kid value to select the
            appropriate public key for verification.</dd>

            <dt>policy</dt>
            <dd>OPTIONAL. Signing policy token declaring what the Signer
            verified about the content before signing. MUST be a registered
            token from the Signing Policy Registry
            (<xref target="signing-policy-registry"/>). When absent,
            verifiers MUST treat the signature as making no claim beyond
            transport integrity.</dd>
          </dl>
        </section>

        <section anchor="algorithm-specific-requirements">
          <name>Algorithm-Specific Requirements</name>
          <t>When alg=ecdsa-p256-sha256:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>The "sig" field MUST contain a base64-encoded DER-encoded ECDSA signature.</li>
            <li>The public key served at key_uri MUST be an uncompressed P-256 public key in PEM format.</li>
          </ul>
          <t>When alg=dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256:</t>
          <ul>
            <li>The "sig" field MUST contain a base64-encoded 64-byte compact
            ECDSA signature in the format r(32 bytes) || s(32 bytes), as
            defined in the DD-ECIES specification <xref target="DD-ECIES"/>.</li>
            <li>The public key served at key_uri MUST be a 33-byte compressed
            secp256k1 public key (0x02 or 0x03 prefix byte) encoded in PEM format.</li>
          </ul>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="client-requirements">
      <name>Client (Verifier) Requirements</name>

      <section anchor="signature-discovery">
        <name>Signature Discovery</name>
        <t>Verifiers MUST check for a Content-Signature header in HTTP responses.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="key-retrieval">
        <name>Public Key Retrieval and Caching</name>
        <ul>
          <li>Verifiers MUST fetch the public key from key_uri (HTTPS RECOMMENDED).</li>
          <li>Verifiers SHOULD cache keys securely for performance.</li>
          <li>Verifiers MAY allow preloading or pinning of trusted keys.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>

      <section anchor="verification-logic">
        <name>Verification Logic</name>
        <t>The Verifier MUST:</t>
        <ol>
          <li>Parse the Content-Signature header.</li>
          <li>Retrieve and cache the public key.</li>
          <li>Verify the decoded "sig" against the exact body of the response.</li>
        </ol>
      </section>

      <section anchor="verification-failure">
        <name>Handling Verification Failure</name>
        <ul>
          <li>Verifiers MUST NOT render or use the resource.</li>
          <li>Verifiers SHOULD display a clear integrity warning or error.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="resource-types">
      <name>Considerations for Specific Resource Types</name>

      <section anchor="static-assets">
        <name>Static Assets (JavaScript, CSS)</name>
        <t>Implementations SHOULD continue to use Subresource Integrity (SRI)
        when possible. WCAP MAY be used as a fallback or enhancement to SRI.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="websockets">
        <name>WebSockets</name>
        <t>To sign WebSocket messages, the signature is included inline:</t>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
{
  "payload": { ... },
  "signature": "<base64 signature of payload>"
}
]]></artwork>
        <t>Every message MUST be signed individually. The receiver MUST
        verify before acting on the message.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="security-considerations">
      <name>Security Considerations</name>
      <dl>
        <dt>Key Compromise</dt>
        <dd>Signers MUST allow for key rotation and revocation.</dd>
        <dt>Replay Attacks</dt>
        <dd>Resources MAY include timestamps or nonces.</dd>
        <dt>Initial Trust</dt>
        <dd>WCAP relies on HTTPS or DNSSEC for the first key fetch.</dd>
        <dt>Signature Stripping</dt>
        <dd>Clients SHOULD treat unsigned content as untrusted when a signature is expected.</dd>
        <dt>Header Binding</dt>
        <dd>Future versions MAY support binding the signature to additional headers (e.g., MIME types, CSP).</dd>
      </dl>
    </section>

    <section anchor="privacy-considerations">
      <name>Privacy Considerations</name>
      <t>Public key fetches can expose access patterns. To reduce this:</t>
      <ul>
        <li>Verifiers SHOULD cache keys aggressively.</li>
        <li>Verifiers MAY pre-fetch public keys for known hosts.</li>
        <li>Alternative key distribution (e.g., IPFS, blockchain, DNSSEC) MAY enhance privacy and resilience.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section anchor="future-extensions">
      <name>Future Extensions (Non-normative)</name>
      <ul>
        <li>Verifiable streaming content using Merkle trees.</li>
        <li>Multi-signature schemes or endorsement chains.</li>
        <li>Web browser integration (e.g., extensions or native WCAP support).</li>
        <li>Blockchain-based or decentralized key registries.</li>
        <li>Cryptographic proof of signing policy compliance (e.g., zero-knowledge
        proofs that decryption succeeded without revealing key material).</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section anchor="signing-policy-registry">
      <name>Signing Policy Declarations</name>

      <section anchor="policy-overview">
        <name>Overview</name>
        <t>A WCAP signature cryptographically proves that the Signer held the
        private key and that the signed bytes were not altered after signing.
        It does not, by itself, say anything about what the Signer verified
        about the content before signing.</t>
        <t>The "policy" parameter in the Content-Signature header allows a
        Signer to declare, as part of the signed response, what it verified
        before signing. The declaration is a registered token from the Signing
        Policy Registry defined in this section.</t>
        <t>Important limitation: A signing policy declaration is a
        self-asserted claim by the Signer. It is not cryptographically
        provable by the Verifier. Verifiers that rely on policy declarations
        MUST establish trust in the Signer's honesty through out-of-band
        means (e.g., audits, published signing policy documentation, or
        reputation). The "policy" parameter is a transparency mechanism,
        not a proof mechanism.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="policy-registry-structure">
        <name>Registry Structure</name>
        <t>Each entry in the Signing Policy Registry MUST include: Token
        (the value used as the "policy" parameter, consisting only of
        lowercase ASCII letters, digits, and hyphens), Name (a short
        human-readable name), Assurance Level (an integer from 0 to 3,
        where 0 means no claim and 3 is the strongest claim), Description
        (a normative statement of what the Signer MUST have verified), and
        Example Use Case (a non-normative example).</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="policy-registered">
        <name>Registered Signing Policies</name>

        <section anchor="policy-none">
          <name>none (Assurance Level 0)</name>
          <t>Token: none. The Signer makes no claim about what was verified
          before signing. The signature attests only to transport integrity.
          This is equivalent to omitting the "policy" parameter entirely.
          Example: A reverse proxy that signs all outbound responses without
          inspecting content.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="policy-content-verified">
          <name>content-verified (Assurance Level 1)</name>
          <t>Token: content-verified. The Signer verified that the content
          was retrievable and well-formed before signing. The Signer MUST
          have successfully fetched or reconstructed the content from its
          authoritative source and confirmed that the retrieval did not
          produce an error. The Signer makes no claim about the content's
          origin or ownership. Example: A file server that reads from a
          local disk and confirms the file exists and is readable before
          signing.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="policy-origin-verified">
          <name>origin-verified (Assurance Level 2)</name>
          <t>Token: origin-verified. The Signer verified that the content
          was retrieved from a known, trusted origin and that the retrieval
          was authenticated. The Signer MUST have confirmed the identity of
          the upstream source (e.g., via a verified signature, authenticated
          storage credential, or cryptographic commitment) before signing.
          Example: A CDN edge node that fetches content from an origin server
          over a mutually authenticated TLS connection and verifies the
          origin's identity certificate before signing.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="policy-decryption-verified">
          <name>decryption-verified (Assurance Level 3)</name>
          <t>Token: decryption-verified. The Signer retrieved the content
          from encrypted storage, successfully decrypted it using the
          appropriate key material, and is signing the plaintext result.
          Successful decryption constitutes cryptographic proof of content
          integrity and authenticity: a ciphertext that decrypts without
          error under the correct key was produced by an entity that held
          that key and has not been tampered with since encryption. The
          Signer MUST NOT set this policy if decryption produced an error
          or if the content was served from a cache without re-verifying
          the ciphertext. Example: A file-serving system that stores files
          as ECIES-encrypted blocks. Before signing the response, the server
          decrypts the block using the member's key material. A successful
          decryption guarantees the block was encrypted by a legitimate
          participant and has not been corrupted or substituted.</t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section anchor="policy-signer-requirements">
        <name>Signer Requirements</name>
        <t>When a Signer includes a "policy" parameter:</t>
        <ol>
          <li>The Signer MUST have performed all verifications described in
          the policy's normative description before signing.</li>
          <li>The Signer MUST NOT assert a policy token for verifications
          it did not perform.</li>
          <li>The Signer SHOULD document its signing policy publicly (e.g.,
          in a "/.well-known/wcap-signing-policy.json" resource).</li>
          <li>If the Signer cannot complete the required verifications, it
          MUST either omit the "policy" parameter, use a lower-assurance
          token, or omit the Content-Signature header entirely.</li>
        </ol>
      </section>

      <section anchor="policy-verifier-requirements">
        <name>Verifier Requirements</name>
        <t>When a Verifier processes a Content-Signature header containing
        a "policy" parameter:</t>
        <ol>
          <li>The Verifier MUST first verify the cryptographic signature
          as defined in Section 7.3. A valid signature is a prerequisite
          for trusting any policy claim.</li>
          <li>The Verifier MAY enforce a minimum assurance level. If the
          declared policy's assurance level is below the required minimum,
          the Verifier SHOULD treat the response as if no policy was
          declared.</li>
          <li>The Verifier MUST NOT treat a policy declaration as
          cryptographic proof of the claimed verifications.</li>
          <li>When a "policy" parameter contains an unrecognized token,
          the Verifier SHOULD treat it as assurance level 0 and MAY log
          a diagnostic warning.</li>
        </ol>
      </section>

      <section anchor="policy-example">
        <name>Example Header with Policy</name>
        <artwork type="ascii-art"><![CDATA[
Content-Signature: alg=dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256;
    key_uri=/.well-known/wcap-public-key-secp256k1.pem;
    sig=<base64 compact signature>;
    policy=decryption-verified
]]></artwork>
        <t>This header declares that the content was retrieved from encrypted
        storage and successfully decrypted before signing.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="policy-extensibility">
        <name>Extensibility</name>
        <t>New signing policy tokens MAY be registered by adding an entry
        with all required fields. Registration MUST NOT require modifications
        to the core protocol sections or the Algorithm Suite Registry.
        Policy tokens are independent of algorithm suites; any policy MAY
        be combined with any algorithm suite.</t>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section anchor="algorithm-suite-registry">
      <name>Algorithm Suite Registry</name>

      <section anchor="registry-overview">
        <name>Overview</name>
        <t>WCAP supports pluggable algorithm suites, analogous to TLS cipher
        suites. An algorithm suite is a named combination of cryptographic
        algorithms — including an elliptic curve, signature algorithm, hash
        function, key format, and signature format — that signers and
        verifiers use to produce and verify content signatures.</t>
        <t>The "alg" parameter in the Content-Signature header is the sole
        mechanism for algorithm negotiation. The core protocol logic MUST NOT
        contain algorithm-specific behavior; all algorithm-dependent details
        are encapsulated within the suite definition.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="registry-structure">
        <name>Registry Structure</name>
        <t>Each algorithm suite entry MUST include:</t>
        <dl>
          <dt>Identifier</dt>
          <dd>The token used as the "alg" parameter value.</dd>
          <dt>Curve</dt>
          <dd>The elliptic curve used for key generation.</dd>
          <dt>Signature Algorithm</dt>
          <dd>The digital signature algorithm.</dd>
          <dt>Hash Algorithm</dt>
          <dd>The hash function used for message digests.</dd>
          <dt>Key Format</dt>
          <dd>The encoding and size of the public key served at key_uri.</dd>
          <dt>Signature Format</dt>
          <dd>The encoding and size of the signature in the "sig" parameter.</dd>
          <dt>Reference</dt>
          <dd>The defining specification or standard.</dd>
        </dl>
      </section>

      <section anchor="registered-suites">
        <name>Registered Algorithm Suites</name>

        <section anchor="suite-p256">
          <name>ecdsa-p256-sha256 (Default)</name>
          <t>Identifier: ecdsa-p256-sha256. Curve: P-256 (secp256r1) per
          <xref target="FIPS186-4"/>. Signature Algorithm: ECDSA. Hash: SHA-256. Key Format:
          PEM-encoded uncompressed P-256 public key. Signature Format:
          DER-encoded ECDSA signature, base64. Reference: <xref target="FIPS186-4"/>,
          <xref target="RFC6979"/>.</t>
          <t>This is the default suite. All conforming verifiers MUST support it.</t>
        </section>

        <section anchor="suite-dd-ecies">
          <name>dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256</name>
          <t>Identifier: dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256. Curve: secp256k1 per
          <xref target="SEC2"/> section 2.4.1. Signature Algorithm: ECDSA
          with deterministic nonce generation per <xref target="RFC6979"/>.
          Hash: SHA-256. Key Format: PEM-encoded 33-byte compressed secp256k1
          public key (0x02/0x03 prefix). Signature Format: 64-byte compact
          signature (r || s, 32 bytes each), base64-encoded. Reference:
          <xref target="DD-ECIES"/>.</t>
          <t>Conforming verifiers SHOULD support this suite.</t>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section anchor="suite-negotiation">
        <name>Algorithm Suite Negotiation</name>
        <t>The "alg" parameter is the sole negotiation mechanism. The core
        protocol (Sections 5-7) MUST NOT contain algorithm-specific behavior.
        All algorithm-dependent logic MUST be delegated to the suite definition.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="unrecognized-suites">
        <name>Handling Unrecognized Algorithm Suites</name>
        <t>When a verifier encounters an unrecognized "alg" value:</t>
        <ol>
          <li>The verifier MUST reject the signature.</li>
          <li>The verifier SHOULD report the unsupported algorithm.</li>
          <li>The verifier MUST NOT attempt verification with a different suite.</li>
        </ol>
      </section>

      <section anchor="registry-extensibility">
        <name>Extensibility</name>
        <t>New algorithm suites MAY be registered by adding an entry with all
        required fields. Registration MUST NOT require modifications to the
        core protocol sections.</t>
      </section>

      <section anchor="verifier-support">
        <name>Verifier Support Requirements</name>
        <ul>
          <li>Verifiers MUST support "ecdsa-p256-sha256".</li>
          <li>Verifiers SHOULD support "dd-ecies-secp256k1-sha256".</li>
          <li>Verifiers MAY support additional registered suites.</li>
        </ul>
      </section>
    </section>

  </middle>

  <back>
    <references>
      <name>References</name>

      <references>
        <name>Normative References</name>

        <xi:include href="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.2119.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.8174.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.6979.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="https://bib.ietf.org/public/rfc/bibxml/reference.RFC.4648.xml"/>

      </references>

      <references>
        <name>Informative References</name>

        <reference anchor="SEC2">
          <front>
            <title>SEC 2: Recommended Elliptic Curve Domain Parameters, Version 2.0</title>
            <author>
              <organization>Certicom Research</organization>
            </author>
            <date year="2010" month="January"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="Standards for Efficient Cryptography" value="SEC 2"/>
          <refcontent>Available at https://www.secg.org/sec2-v2.pdf</refcontent>
        </reference>

        <reference anchor="DD-ECIES">
          <front>
            <title>DD-ECIES: Digital Defiance Elliptic Curve Integrated Encryption Scheme</title>
            <author>
              <organization>Digital Defiance</organization>
            </author>
            <date year="2025"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="Version" value="1.0"/>
        </reference>

        <reference anchor="FIPS186-4">
          <front>
            <title>Digital Signature Standard (DSS)</title>
            <author>
              <organization>National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
            </author>
            <date year="2013" month="July"/>
          </front>
          <seriesInfo name="FIPS PUB" value="186-4"/>
        </reference>

      </references>
    </references>

  </back>
</rfc>
